Look at the ordeal we have to keep him alive.
Onu yaşatmak için çektiğimiz çileye bak.
Oh cruel world, ah!
Ah zalım dünya, ah!
I knead the steel and knead it, Batur Bey.
Çeliği hamur edip yoğurdum Batur Bey.
If the whole world comes together ...
Tüm cihan bir araya gelse...
... no one can wear his wrist unofficially.
...bileğini kimse bükemez gayrı.
If Cenkte puts me half way ...
Cenkte beni yarı yolda koyarsa...
... then no one can take you away, blacksmith.
...o vakit seni elimden kimse alamaz he demirci.
Which trouble did you get in again?
Yine hangi belaya bulaştınız acaba?
It was all a lie.
Hepsi yalandı.
Kalanoz!
Kalanoz!
Listen to me.
Beni dinle.
Damn you.
Lanet olsun sana.
Stop!
Durun!
Who are you?
Kimsiniz siz?
The one that will put Byzantine back on its feet ...
Bizans'ı yeniden ayağa kaldıracak olan...
... we are the only power.
...tek gücüz.
Commander Kalanoz.
Komutan Kalanoz.
It is big...
O büyük...
... of that sacred power ...
...o kutsal gücün...
... we are the only owners.
...tek sahipleriyiz.
Fighting against the Turks ...
Türklere karşı savaşıp...
... to restore our empire to its former power ...
...imparatorluğumuzu eski gücüne kavuşturmak...
... to protect Hagia Sophia in Constantinople ...
...Konstantinopolis'te Ayasofya'yı korumak için...
... we swore to death.
...ölümüne and içtik.
Who are you?
Sen kimsin?
Yannis.
Yannis.
The monk Yannis.
Keşiş Yannis.
The Margarite Church in Serres ...
Serez'deki Margarit Kilise'sinin...
I'm a loyal servant.
...sadık bir hizmetkarıyım.
Everyone you see here ...
Burada gördüğün herkes...
... on behalf of our church ...
...kilisemiz adına...
... are the guards of Kulucahisar.
...Kulucahisar'ın bekçileridir.
Kulucahisar is just one of the castles under our control.
Kulucahisar kontrolümüz altında olan kalelerden sadece biri.
With many more castle commanders ...
Daha birçok kale komutanlarıyla...
... with their soldiers and even their tekfur ...
...askerleriyle ve hatta tekfurlarıyla...
... is in our disposal.
...emrimizdedir.
Sofia.
Sofya.
What about you?
Ya sen?
Growing with Turkish hatred ...
Türk nefretiyle büyüyen...
I am a woman who obeyed Master Yannis to the end.
...Efendi Yannis'e sonuna kadar itaat etmiş bir kadınım.
To the man I fell in love with ...
Aşık olduğum adama...
... a woman who has not been able to open it for years.
...bu uğurda yıllarca içini açamamış bir kadın.
To a commander like you ...
Senin gibi bir komutana...
... joining us, adding strength to our strength ...
...bize katılmayı, gücümüze güç katmayı...
... until the last drop of our blood with us ...
...bizimle kanımızın son damlasına kadar...
... I propose to fight the Turks.
...Türklerle savaşmayı teklif ediyorum.
Commander Kalanoz.
Komutan Kalanoz.
Say it to me.
De bana.
What was your wish in the castle?
Kaledeki muradınız neydi?
Obviously you got something secret from there.
Belli ki oradan gizli bir şey aldınız.
Or...
Yoksa...
... treasure?
...hazine mi?
You know, Osman.
Bildin Osman.
Is the Treasury. But what did we steal that treasure?
Hazinedir. Lakin o hazineyi ne çaldık...
neither did we extort.
...ne de gasp ettik.
With the help of Allah's grace and help ...
Allah'ın inayeti ve yardımıyla...
... we took back what was ours.
...bizim olanı geri aldık.
All of the treasure ...
Hazinenin hepsi...
... belong to the people.
...ahilere aittir.
I know the Ahis ...
Ahileri de bilirim...
... their resistance to the Mongols ...
...Moğollara direnişlerini de...
... but my skin gets scarred Edabali.
...lakin derunum debelenir Edabali.
Why do the people in the castle hostile you?
Kaledekiler neden size düşmanlık güder?
Why did they steal your treasure?
Hazinenizi neden çaldılar?
What happened at the castle?
Kalede ne oldu?
Your daughter Bala ...
Kızınız Bala...
... what was your lover Tursun there for?
...yareniniz Tursun ne için oradaydı?
A dark power that reigns in Bitinya ...
Bitinya'da hüküm süren karanlık bir güç...
... infiltrated everywhere, every corner.
...her yere sızmış, her köşeye.
You take a look ...
Bir bakarsın...
... they reign with their ideas, you take a look ...
...fikirleriyle hüküm sürerler, bir bakarsın...
... with their men.
...devşirdikleri adamlarıyla.
What do they want?
Ne isterler?
What are their Murat's?
Muratları nedir bu melunların?
In the darkness they put on us ...
Üstümüze saldıkları karanlıkta...
... they want to strangle the order in us, son.
...içimizdeki nizamı alem ışığını boğmak isterler oğul.
They expel the Turks from this land ...
Türkleri bu topraklardan kovup...
... they want to revive the Byzantine spirit.
...Bizans ruhunu yeniden diriltmek isterler.
They know that the Ahis will not bow.
Ahilerin boyun eğmeyeceğini bilirler.
To be a bent in front of us ...
Önümüzde bent olmak için...
They stole the treasure, which was the capital of the Ahis.
...Ahilerin sermayesi olan hazineyi çaldılar.
Us...
Bizi...
... they want to drag economic crisis, son.
...ittisadi bunalıma sürüklemek isterler oğul.
Even Sofia, who killed Tekfur and took over Kulucahisar Castle ...
Tekfur'u öldürüp Kulucahisar Kalesi'ni ele geçiren Sofya bile...
... their representative in the castle.
...onların kaledeki temsilcisi.
Those who stole this treasure from you ...
Bu hazineyi sizden çalanlar...
... as you described ...
...anlattığın gibi...
Edabali, a dark and great power.
...karanlık ve büyük bir güç Edabali.
The power behind those who lean back on Hakk ...
Sırtını Hakk'a yaslayanların arkasındaki güç...
... always bigger son.
...daima daha büyüktür oğul.
What anxiety we have,
Ne kaygımız vardır,...
nor our fear. Because we know and believe that ...
...ne de korkumuz. Zira biz bilir ve iman ederiz ki...
... even though the swearing armies are shattered ...
...küfür orduları azıp kudursa da...
... where all truth takes refuge ...
...her hakikatin sığındığı...
There is a Hira Cave.
...bir Hira Mağarası vardır.
What you told me warmed my heart.
Anlattıkların bağrımı ısıttı.
It is born inside me that ...
İçime öyle bir doğar ki...
... in so many galleries ...
...bunca gailenin içinde...
... we need ...
...bize lazım gelen...
... is a strong union.
...güçlü bir birliktir.
No mob will shake ...
Hiçbir güruhun sarsamayacağı...
... kaviar ...
...kavi...
... an imposing principality.
...heybetli bir beylik.
Maybe...
Belki...
maybe a state.
...belki de bir devlet.
It...
Bu...
... there must be such a state that ...
...öyle bir devlet olmalı ki...
justice must be resurrected with it.
...adalet onunla yeniden dirilmeli.
Islam should find peace ...
Alemi İslam huzur bulmalı...
... the oppressors should tremble with fear ...
...zalimler korkudan titremeli...
...morality...
...ahlak...
... he must stand up with him.
...onunla kıyama kalkmalı.
Surprise Commander Kalanoz.
Şaşırma Komutan Kalanoz.
Just answer.
Sadece cevap ver.
Are you with us
Bizimle misin?
Let's say I am not.
Diyelim ki değilim.
Are you going to kill me too?
Beni de mi öldüreceksiniz?
Any commander who is Greek and has no Turkish hatred ...
Rum olup içinde Türk nefreti olmayan hiçbir komutanın...
... has no right to live, Kalanoz.
...yaşamaya hakkı yoktur Kalanoz.
We set out for a big case.
Biz büyük bir dava için yola çıktık.
And our enemies are so close ...
Ve düşmanlarımız o kadar yakın ki...
... our ideals are dubbed in our heart ...
...ideallerimiz lakaplı kalbimizde...
... there is no room for mercy.
...zerrece merhamete yer yok.
Who are these enemies?
Kimmiş bu düşmanlar?
Sheikh Edabali.
Şeyh Edabali.
And his priests.
Ve ahileri.
An old sheikh and a handful of ahms.
Yaşlı bir şeyh ve bir avuç ahi.
Why made you so nervous, Monk Yannis?
Sizi neden bu kadar tedirgin etti, Keşiş Yannis?
You don't know them, Kalanoz.
Onları tanımıyorsun Kalanoz.
Sheikh Edabali ...
Şeyh Edabali...
... is the Turks' undeliverable spirit.
...Türklerin teslim alınamayan ruhudur.
Even the Mongols could not cope with the ahis.
Moğollar bile ahilerle baş edemedi.
So much so that when we say it's over ...
Öyle ki bizim bitti dediğimiz yerde...
they start again.
...onlar yeniden bir başlangıç yapar.
So how do you deal with it?
Peki o zaman, siz nasıl baş edeceksiniz?
For the sake of ideals like you ...
Senin gibi idealleri uğruna...
... with heroes who will die.
...can olup can verecek kahramanlarla.
We Greeks have an ancient saying.
Biz Rumların kadim bir sözü vardır.
Wolf hunting ...
Kurt avına çıkan...
... you should know your ax.
...baltasını bilesin.
If we don't know our axes ...
Eğer baltalarımızı bilemezsek...
... we cannot keep Turks in front.
...Türklerin önünü tutamayız.
And if we can not keep Sheikh Edabali and his philanthropists ...
Ve tutamadığımız takdirde Şeyh Edabali ve ahileri...
... with the veterans, the alps ...
...uçtaki gazilerle, alplerle...
... and it is in alliance with the abyss ...
...ve bacıyanlarla ittifak içinde olur ki...
... this will be our apocalypse.
...bu da bizim kıyametimiz olur.
Now...
Şimdi...
... I ask my question from the beginning, Commander Kalanoz.
...sorumu baştan soruyorum Komutan Kalanoz.
Years later, do you want to be called a traitor?
Yıllar sonra, bir hain olarak mı anılmak istersin?
Otherwise, stopping the influx of the Turks ...
Yoksa Türklerin akınlarını durduran...
as a hero?
...bir kahraman olarak mı?
On this holy road ...
Bu kutsal yolda...
I'm with you to death.
...ölümüne sizinleyim.
Shut up!
Kes sesini kes!
Shut up.
Kapa çeneni.
Now Osman Bey would not need you ...
İmdi Osman Bey'imin sana ihtiyacı olmayacaktı ki...
... I was going to swim alive.
...canlı canlı derini yüzecektim.
I told you everything I know.
Bildiğim her şeyi size söyledim.
Let me go!
Bırakın beni!
Ornamental! Ornamental! Ornamental!
Sus! Sus! Sus!
Hungry! Hungry!
Aç! Aç!
Hungry!
Aç!
Now sit well behaved here.
İmdi uslu uslu otur burada.
One question.
Tek sual.
One answer.
Tek cevap.
Who are you?
Kimsin sen?
Selamun aleykum.
Selamun aleyküm.
Yarenler.
Yarenler.
Hello, hello.
Aleyküm selam.
You can distinguish the warp two-folded ones and the wefts with a single twist well.
Çözgülü iki katlı olanla atkıları tek bükümlü olanları iyi ayırasınız.
Weavings with kufi motifs and those with oak motifs are still raw.
Meşk motifli olanla kufi motifli olan dokumalar henüz hamdır.
Selling them in the market in this way does not suit us.
Bunları bu şekilde pazarda satmak bize yakışmaz.
Bala Hatun on her head.
Başüstüne Bala Hatun.
The skin of casual and fraud is not suitable for the market.
Meşin ve sahtiyanlığın cildi pazar için münasip değil.
Draw the strange guraba and distribute it to his reward.
Garip gurabaya çizme yapıp sevabına dağıtın.
Aye.
Başüstüne.
Bala Hatun on her head.
Başüstüne Bala Hatun.
Not just pusat shaking.
Sadece pusat sallamada değil.
You are skilled in trade, Bala Hatun.
Ticarette de mahirmişsin Bala Hatun.
Pusatla our dear, Turkish fortune in trade ...
Pusatla canımızı, ticarette Türk'ün ikbalini...
We protect our ceremony with Osman, Osman.
...edeple de töremizi koruruz Osman Bey.
Turkish ceremony ...
Türk'ün töresi...
... first of all, he said on the shoulders of the girls, my dear.
...evvela hatunların omuzlarındadır derdi hayım anam.
Thanks to you, I saw how right he was.
Sayende onun ne kadar haklı olduğunu gördüm.
Bala Hatun.
Bala Hatun.
Take the Horse ...
Atın Alaca...
What happened to Alaca?
Ne olmuş Alaca'ya?
Ahvali is not good.
Ahvali iyi değildir.
In the barn.
Ahırda.
Where it passes, weed, my dear friend.
Geçtiği yerde ot bitmez can yoldaşım.
The wing of Bala Hatun is Alaca.
Bala Hatun'un kanadı, Alaca'm.
Did I have a destiny to see you like this?
Seni bu halde görmek de mi vardı kaderimde?
Osman Bey jumped out of the epic Manas and entered my life.
Manas destanından fırlayıp girdi hayatıma Osman Bey.
Kanıkeydin Taytoru was for me.
Kanıkeydin Taytoru'ydu benim için.
What an ornament in the sky ...
Gökte nasıl bir süsse ay...
I would have been crescent with light on dark roads.
Alacam da karanlık yollarda ışığıyla hilalimdi.
Spruce...
Alacam...
... let me excuse you, Bala Hatun.
...hele bir müsaade edesin Bala Hatun.
Does the moon get angry because the black cloud collapses in front of the moon in the sky?
Gökteki ayın önüne kara bulut çöktü diye aya küsülür mü hiç?
Pied.
Alaca.
You missed a lot of troubles with Bala Hatun ...
Bala Hatun ile birlikte nice badireler atlattığın...
... it is obvious from the wounds you entered in many wars.
...nice cenklere girdiğin yaralarından belli.
You are brave as you own.
Sen de sahibin gibi cesursun.
Your eye is black.
Gözün kara.
You will not give up, you will not surrender.
Pes etmezsin, teslim olmazsın.
Bala Hatun is certain that you gave your horse the right.
Atına hakkını verdiğin belli Bala Hatun.
You like your friend, you ride like your enemy.
Dostun gibi sever, düşmanın gibi binersin.
He has suffered so much ...
O da bunca cefayı çekmiş...
... thrown the pain ...
...acıyı içine atmış...
... despite the inflammation in his blood, he did not speak.
...kanındaki iltihaba rağmen ses etmemiş.
For you...
Senin için...
If you have faith ...
Eğer itimadın varsa...
... as you saved me from mud ...
...beni çamurdan kurtardığın gibi...
... let me do well.
...Alaca'yı iyi etmeme izin ver.
I didn't trust you ...
Sana itimadım var ki...
... I brought it to my father's slope, Osman Bey.
...babamın yamacına getirmişim Osman Bey.
My horse is entrusted to you.
Atım sana emanettir.
Pied ...
Alaca...
Inflammation in your blood will be good.
Kanındaki iltihaba iyi gelecek.
Now...
İmdi...
I say, let's take you and go to the place.
...derim ki seni alıp obaya gidelim.
I'll treat it there.
Orada tedavi edeyim.
Let me ...
Edeyim ki...
... from the beautiful eyes of the owner, Bala Hatun ...
...sahibin Bala Hatun'un güzel gözlerinden...
... let's not shed once again.
...bir kez daha yaş dökülmesin.
May Allah give you whatever you want Osman Bey.
Allah ne muradın varsa versin Osman Bey.
My only wish ...
Tek muradım...
... come to the new market tomorrow and let me see you again.
...yarın yeni pazara gelip seni bir kez daha görmeme izin vermen.
My non-comrade is entrusted to you.
Gayrı can yoldaşım sana emanettir.
Excuse me, Osman Bey.
Müsaade senindir Osman Bey.
If I have two hands in the blood ...
İki elim kanda olsa...
... I will bring pied.
...Alaca'yı getireceğim.
When you say be ...
Ol deyince olduran...
... of Allah Almighty, who filled our hearts with the light of faith ...
...gönüllerimizi iman nuruyla dolduran Yüce Allah'ın...
... by the name of ninety-nine.
...doksan dokuz adıyla.
Pusat equipped and ...
Pusat kuşanıp...
... to cut their sentences ...
...cezalarını kesmek için...
... everyone waits for orders.
...herkes emir bekler.
However, Dundar Bey you are like distractions.
Lakin Dündar Bey bizi oyalar gibisin.
Your pain ...
Acını da...
... I understand your anger too, Bamsı Bey.
...öfkeni de anlarım Bamsı Bey.
But without knowing the original work ...
Lakin işin aslını öğrenmeden...
... is it wise to want a war?
...cenk istemek, akıl karı mıdır?
Mr. Dundar.
Dündar Bey.
What you call Cenk was just the needy thing, many little people could not overthrow many.
Cenk dediğin sadece akla muhtaç olaydı nice azlar nice çokları deviremez idi.
The lack of our assembly ...
Bizim meclisimizin eksiği...
... heart is Dundar Bey.
...yürektir Dündar Bey.
The lack is heart.
Eksiği yürektir.
My father...
Babam...
... Dundar Bey ...
...Dündar Bey...
... his heart ...
...yüreğini de...
... put his head on the road of our Ertuğrul Bey.
...başını da Ertuğrul Bey'imizin yoluna koymuştur.
Starting this way ...
Bu yola baş koyarak...
... just as a child ...
...daha çocuk yaşında...
... has proved its fatality.
...bahadırlığını ispat etmiştir.
Now...
İmdi...
... no one should try to question my father's courage.
...kimse babamın cesaretini sorgulamaya kalkmasın.
We said let's trade.
Ticaret edelim dedik.
They attempted to assassinate.
Suikast yapmaya kalktılar.
Our Aybars were martyred.
Aybars'ımız şehit oldu.
My brother Osman, on the other hand, stays in an unknown well.
Kardeşim Osman ise bilinmez bir kuyunun içinde debelenir durur.
Cenk is our profession.
Cenk bizim mesleğimizdir.
Not that...
Lakin...
patience is also our guide.
...sabır da rehberimizdir.
Until I get news from Osman ...
Osman'dan bir haber alana kadar...
... I will not act.
...harekete geçmeyelim derim ben.
Thank God.
Şükürler olsun.
Osman Bey is coming! Osman Bey is coming!
Osman Bey geliyor! Osman Bey geliyor!
Thank God!
Şükürler olsun!
Well, sir! Welcome sir!
Maşallah beyime! Hoş geldin beyim!
Take it to the barn.
Ahıra götüresin.
Neither brother, we leave Osman to the shroud.
Ne kardeşim Osman'ı keferenin eline bırakırız.
Nor...
Ne de...
... now we can afford cen
...imdi cenki göze alabiliriz.
My nephew is right.
Yeğenim haklıdır.
To say Cenk ...
Cenk demek için...
...time...
...vakit...
... is very early.
...hayli erkendir.
Until Osman returns ...
Osman dönünceye kadar...
... it is good to stay vigilant.
...teyakkuzda kalmakta fayda var derim.
Oy Osman.
Oy Osman'ım.
While the rooster is in love ...
Kahpelik aşikarken...
Dundar Bey is the pass of the vigilant brave.
...teyakkuz yiğidin pasıdır Dündar Bey.
Cenk?
Cenk mi?
Peace?
Sulh mü?
You should also listen to me.
Bir de benden dinleyesiniz.
Here you go.
Buyur.
I promise ...
Sözüm...
... brave gentlemen here.
...buradaki yiğit beyleredir.
With fitna radiating from Kulucahisar ...
Kulucahisar'dan yayılan fitne ile...
... it's time to fight.
...cenk etmenin vakti gelmiştir.
Not that...
Lakin...
... combat with a simple sword ...
...yalın kılıçla cenk etmek...
... will enliven the life of the sinister enemy.
...uğursuz düşmanın canına can katacaktır.
What do you mean, Osman?
Ne demek istersin Osman?
Cuts in ...
Kestikçe...
... as you cut pieces of flesh ...
...etinden parça kopardıkça...
... with stronger limbs than before ...
...eskisinden daha güçlü uzuvlarıyla...
... will strangle us ...
...bizi boğacak...
... we have a tough enemy.
...çetin bir düşman vardır karşımızda.
The coffins behind the walls ...
Surların ardındaki kahpelerin...
... it's time to cut his heart with a dagger.
...yüreğini hançerle kesip alma vaktidir.
It is imperative that the gentlemen here make a war decision today.
Buradaki beylerin bugün buradan cenk kararı çıkarması şarttır.
Not that...
Lakin...
... the decision of this ...
...bunun kararını...
... Dundar Bey will give.
...Dündar Bey verecektir.
Joyful...
Sen...
... how did you grow and mature like plum plum bro?
...ne ara mürdüm eriği gibi büyüyüp olgunlaştın kardeşim?
In this land ...
Bu topraklarda...
... there is no room for both rawness and brotherhood.
...hamlığa da toyluğa da yer yoktur ağabey.
The biggest toy is to go blindly to the well of the shroud with the rope of trade.
En büyük toyluk, körü körüne ticaretin ipi ile keferenin kuyusuna girmektir.
Today from this toy ...
Bugün bu toydan...
... a warrant must be issued for the recruitment of Turk.
...Türk'ün ikbali için cenk kararı çıkmalıdır.
Otherwise...
Aksi halde...
... you dig your grave, you know.
...mezarınızı kazarsınız bilesiniz.
He killed his own tekfur and ...
Kendi tekfurlarını öldürüp...
... we are faced with traps against us with all kinds of tricks.
...bize karşı türlü hilelerle tuzak kuranlarla karşı karşıyayız.
This cen ...
Bu cenki...
... they started by killing my brother Aybars.
...kardeşim Aybars'ı öldürerek onlar başlattı.
We...
Biz...
... we will stand up for the gas.
...gaza için kıyama kalkacağız.
Now...
İmdi...
... not war ...
...cenk değil...
... is the time of martyrdom.
...şehadet vaktidir.
This is what I will say.
Diyeceğim budur.
Kayı gentlemen's hand ...
Kayı beylerin eli...
... for cenk ...
...cenk için...
... he must get up for gas.
...gaza için kalkmalıdır.
It's time to kick off for the gas!
Gayrı gaza için kıyam vaktidir!
Osman Bey says right.
Osman Bey doğru der.
He won't be comfortable with the shroud.
Kefere rahat durmayacak.
Thank you Osman Bey, time is time to fight.
Eyvallah Osman Bey, vakit cenk vaktidir.
Say it now.
İmdi söyleyin.
Cenk?
Cenk mi?
Peace?
Sulh mü?
Cenkse cenk. The trust of our Ertuğrul Bey ...
Cenkse cenk. Ertuğrul Bey'imizin emaneti...
... than to give our Osman to the voyage ...
...Osman'ımızı kefereye vermektense...
... giving our lives is a must.
...canlarımızı vermek evladır.
I see ...
Görürüm ki...
... gentlemen have made up their mind.
...beyler kararını vermiştir.
Not that...
Lakin...
... this decision ...
...bu karar...
... exceeds my height.
...benim boyumu aşar.
Until Ertuğrul Bey returns ...
Ertuğrul Bey dönünceye kadar...
... we need to know patience.
...sabretmeyi bilmemiz lazım.
Cenk decision ...
Cenk kararı...
... ceremonies are brains.
...törece beyindir.
Now...
İmdi...
... let me.
...müsaade edesiniz.
I would like to talk to my nephews.
Yeğenlerimle konuşmak isterim.
Bismillahirrahmanirrahim.
Bismillahirrahmanirrahim.
[Ya Allah ...]
[Ya Allah...]
You are my daughter.
Buyurasın kızım.
Thanks to ...
Sayende...
... the trust of Pir-i Turkistan Ahmet Yesevi ...
...Pir-i Türkistan Ahmet Yesevi hazretlerinin emaneti...
... this wooden sword is in our hands now.
...bu tahta kılıç artık elimizde kızım.
I hope you pray with your prayer, father.
Duanla, himmetinle inşallah baba.
The most acceptable patronage is the effort of one's son ...
En makbul himmet, kişi oğlunun gayreti...
... the most sincere prayer ...
...en samimi dua da...
... verb daughter.
...fiilidir kızım.
You did a real job.
Hakikatli bir iş başardın.
Because this is a wooden sword.
Zira bu tahta kılıç.
Entering into the shouts with their steel lures ...
Çelikten yalmanlarıyla bağırlara giren...
... is not like black pusat.
...kara pusatlara benzemez.
This sword ...
Bu kılıç...
... occurs in the most depressed times.
...en buhranlı vakitlerde ortaya çıkar.
And it reaches the new hakan of the Turks.
Ve Türklerin yeni hakanına ulaşır.
When he decorated the back of the Turks' new hakan with the grace of the folly ...
Hak çalabının inayetiyle Türklerin yeni hakanının belini süslediğinde...
... to destroy the swearing towns ...
...küfür beldelerini yıkıp...
... will enter into hearts.
...gönüllere girecek.
With the spiritual shit he spreads from here ...
Buradan yaydığı manevi şavk ile...
... cruel fear ...
...zalime korku...
will give hope to the oppressed.
...mazluma umut verecek.
In so much effort ...
Bunca gayenin içinde...
... how do we find that right, dad?
...o hakanı nasıl bulacağız baba?
Does it have a wisdom or secret?
Bunun bir hikmeti, sırrı var mıdır?
We'll find it, girl.
Bulacağız kızım.
Despite all the zemheri ...
Onca zemheriye rağmen...
... managed not to go out ...
...sönmemeyi başarmış...
... we'll find that spark.
...o kıvılcımı bulacağız.
Because this wooden sword ...
Çünkü bu tahta kılıcı...
... when we put that spark on his waist ...
...o kıvılcımın beline taktığımızda...
... that spark ...
...o kıvılcım...
... turning into a volcano ...
...bir volkana dönüşüp...
... donut on the oppressed ...
...mazlumların üzerine çöreklenen...
... will burn the veil of captivity and possession.
...esaret ve zillet perdesini yakacak.
Who is this hakan?
Bu hakan kim ola baba?
In the fight of truth and superstition, who does not resist shaking pusat ...
Hak ile batılın kavgasında pusat sallamaktan yılmayan...
... not only with his heart ...
...sadece yüreğiyle değil...
... who can work with his mind and rest his back on the oppressed ...
...aklıyla da iş görebilen ve sırtını mazlumlara dayayan...
... one person.
...bir er kişidir.
Er son ...
Er oğlu...
... is a person!
...er kişidir!
When Ahval is like this ...
Ahval böyle olunca...
... I say ...
...derim ki...
... let's put Kulucahisar Castle in the Islamic town.
...Kulucahisar Kalesi'ni İslam beldesi eyleyelim.
If we are victorious ...
Eğer muzaffer olursak...
... we drop all the castles.
...bir bir bütün kaleleri düşürürüz.
Thus, from Mongolian tasallut ...
Böylece Moğol tasallutundan da...
... we will be saved from the Byzantine assault.
...Bizans taarruzundan da kurtulmuş oluruz.
Islamic banner ...
İslam sancağını...
... we wave everywhere.
...her yerde dalgalandırırız.
Stop, nephew ...
Dur hele yeğen...
...Stop.
...dur.
What is this paper clip?
Bu ne ataş?
Even you will stay on the murder ...
Sen cinayetin üzerine kalacağını bile bile...
... did you stay in that castle?
...o kalede kaldın öyle mi?
I'm left sure.
Kaldım emmi.
Because the killer of tekfur ...
Çünkü tekfurun katili...
... my brother is the killer of Aybars.
...kardeşim Aybars'ın da katilidir.
Osman.
Osman.
There is nothing you hide from us, brother?
Bizden sakladığın bir hal yok değil mi kardeşim?
What else will I keep on all this information, brother?
Bunca malumatın üzerine daha ne saklayacağım ağabey?
We give on ...
Üstüne verdiğimiz...
... all labor ...
...bütün emekler...
Halal to you, Osman.
...sana helal olsun Osman.
In the pusat you carry ...
Taşıdığın pusatın da...
... you also gave the right to be the son of a gentleman.
...bey oğlu olmanın da hakkını verdin.
I am proud of you as Emmin.
Emmin olarak seninle iftihar ederim.
Did he suck in spite of kidnapping Aygül?
Aygül'ü kaçırmalarına rağmen mi emmi?
My nephew, my nephew at the enemy.
Düşmanda kahpelik bitmez yeğenim.
You do not have a genius in what happened to my daughter.
Kızımın başına gelenlerde senin bir dahilin yoktur.
Thank you.
Eyvallah emmi.
Into the fitna in the castle ...
Kaledeki fitnenin içine...
... you plunged like a blind dagger.
...kör bir hançer gibi daldın.
In every misfortune that has happened ...
Kefereler olan biten her musibette...
... they marked you.
...seni mimlediler.
That is what I mean ...
Demem odur ki...
... Ertuğrul Bey, beware of himself until he returns.
...Ertuğrul Bey dönünceye kadar kendini sakınasın.
I trust you, Osman.
Sana güvenirim Osman.
To yourself ...
Kendine de...
... to your alps ...
...alplerine de...
... be the judge.
...hakim olasın.
Don't worry, sure.
Merak etmeyesin emmi.
Unless there is a crap from the castle ...
Kaleden bir kahpelik gelmediği sürece...
... to myself ...
...kendime de...
... I will be compared to my alps.
...alplerime de mukayyet olurum.
God...
Allah...
... help us.
...yardımcımız olsun.
I want your permission too.
Ben de müsaadeni isterim emmi.
And what they hide from me ...
Benden sakladıklarını da...
... how he got into trouble ...
...nasıl bir belaya bulaştığını da...
... I will learn Osman.
...öğreneceğim Osman.
At that time...
O vakit...
...I will talk to you.
...seninle görüşeceğiz.
We will comment.
Görüşeceğiz.
Master Yannis, the light on your face ...
Efendi Yannis, yüzünüzdeki ışık...
... he tells me that the incoming information is important.
...gelen bilginin önemli olduğunu söylüyor bana.
Our man in the market, Nizamettin.
Pazardaki adamımız Nizamettin.
He wrote that the Ahis were in the new market.
Ahilerin yeni pazarda olduğunu yazmış.
Osman was also with them.
Osman da onlarla birlikteymiş.
As I guessed.
Tahmin ettiğim gibi.
Osman is with them.
Osman da onlarla birlikte.
It is obvious that the Ahis are organized in the new market.
Ahilerin yeni pazarda örgütlendikleri belli.
We need to prevent this.
Buna mani olmamız gerek.
We will be Kalanoz, we will.
Olacağız Kalanoz, olacağız.
Destroying the market and ...
Pazarı yerle bir edip...
... we will kill them all.
...hepsini öldüreceğiz.
If I attack my soldiers, this will be the cause of war, but ...
Askerlerimle saldırırsam bu savaş nedeni olur ama...
I'm ready for war.
...ben savaşa hazırım.
It's early for war yet.
Henüz savaş için erken.
And this is not your job ...
Hem bu işi sen değil...
... others will.
...başkaları yapacak.
Who can do this other than me, Master Yannis?
Bunu benden başka kim yapabilir Efendi Yannis?
The bloody sword of Catalonia ...
Katalonya'nın kanlı kılıcı...
Prince Salvador.
...Prens Salvador.
I am at your disposal with my fearless warriors, Master Yannis.
Korkusuz savaşçılarımla emrinizdeyim Efendi Yannis.
Pied!
Alaca!
That's it.
İşte böyle.
Emmim grabs my back.
Emmim sırtımı sıvazlar.
Honey drips from your tongue.
Dilinden bal damlar Alaca.
Not a good sign, huh?
Pek hayra alamet değil he?
Not a good sign.
Pek hayra alamet değil.
But my absorption is smart man.
Lakin emmim zeki adamdır.
First I keep my heart nice ...
Önce gönlümü hoş tutup...
... is chasing what it will do.
...edeceğini etmenin peşindedir.
Hullo.
Maşallah.
Do not worry, you will recover in time.
Tasalanmayasın tez vakitte iyileşeceksin.
Come on, let's.
Haydi bakalım.
Mr. Osman.
Osman Bey.
I was going to lose my mind while I was waiting for you.
Seni beklerken aklımı kaçıracaktım.
Are you angry with me?
Sen bana kızdın mı olanlar için?
There is nothing left for me.
Benim yüzümden başına gelmeyen kalmadı.
It is counted if I live.
Yaşıyorsam sayendedir.
May Allah be pleased with you.
Allah senden razı olsun.
You are in my blood, you are in my life Aygül Hatun.
Sen benim kanımdansın, canımdansın Aygül Hatun.
First of all, your life comes.
Evvela senin canın gelir.
Who is this horse?
Bu at kimindir?
Poisoned.
Zehirlenmiş.
From the grass he ate.
Yediği otlardan.
A cookie girl I met on the way.
Yolda karşılaştığım bir çerçi kızın.
I said that Ointment of Zühre is good for him.
Dedim ki Zühre yengemin merhemi ona iyi gelir.
I will take it tomorrow and take it to the new market.
Yarın alıp onu yeni pazara götüreceğim.
I will give it to the owner.
Sahibine vereceğim.
Come easy Osman Bey.
Kolay gele Osman Bey.
Thank you.
Eyvallah.
Horse...
At...
...one...
...bir...
... the Chechhar daughter.
...çerçi kızınınmış.
The Chechen girl, huh?
Çerçi kızı ha?
Open your eyes, Aygül. One sooner ...
Gözünü açasın Aygül. Bir er...
... if he carries the name of a chick to the oba ...
...bir hatunun adını obasına kadar taşırsa...
... know that fire fell into your heart.
...bil ki gönlüne ateş düşmüştür.
Pied.
Alaca.
Come.
Gel.
Lets.
Haydi.
Come on beauty.
Haydi güzelim.
Welcome, Gonca Hatun.
Hoş gelmişsin Gonca Hatun.
If you were a breath, Bala Hatun.
Hele bir soluklansaydın Bala Hatun.
We've gotten through all that bad.
Onca badire atlattık.
You don't know how I miss sitting on my job, Gonca Hatun.
İşimin başına oturmayı nasıl özlemişim bilemezsin Gonca Hatun.
Who are they, Bala Hatun?
Kim bunlar Bala Hatun?
Two lovers.
İki aşık.
Aslı and Kerem.
Aslı ile Kerem.
Since the lovers ...
Madem aşıklar...
... why do they stand apart?
...neden ayrı dururlar?
I heard his stories from a Aleppo traveler.
Öykülerini Halepli bir seyyahtan işittiydim.
Without coming to Vuslata ...
Vuslata ermeden...
... It became ash with the longing of Kerem Aslı.
...Kerem Aslı'nın hasreti ile kül olmuş.
Aslı also brushed her hair and swept these ashes.
Aslı da saçını süpürge edip bu külleri süpürmüş.
You will understand that the figures are apocalyptic ...
Anlayacağın vuslatları mahşere...
... their stories are up to us.
...hikayeleri bize kalmış.
What should I say, Bala?
Ne diyeyim Bala?
May God grant love.
Allah aşkın da kavuşmalısını nasip etsin.
Amine.
Amin.
When Osman Bey arrives ...
Osman Bey obaya vardığında...
I hope he will not be subjected to the suckling of his suckling.
...inşallah emmisinin gadrine uğramaz.
Osman Bey evelallah, stuck like a dagger in the heart of the shroud.
Osman Bey keferenin yüreğine hançer gibi saplanmış evelallah.
You don't worry.
Merak etmeyesin.
They will also overcome them.
Bunların da üstesinden gelecektir.
Both ...
Hem...
... my sheikh opened his heart to him.
...şeyhim de ona yüreğini açtı.
If he did not see the ore that would carry our secret ...
Sırrımızı taşıyacak cevheri görmeseydi...
... would he open his heart Gonca Hatun?
...yüreğini açar mıydı Gonca Hatun?
Teokles still has not arrived, sir.
Teokles hala gelmemiş efendim.
What if Teokles fell into Osman's hands?
Ya Teokles Osman'ın eline geçtiyse?
Damn it!
Lanet olsun!
If it makes him talk, things get mixed up.
Eğer onu konuşturursa işler iyice karışır.
It would be impossible for us to find the treasure.
Hazineyi bulmamız imkansız olur.
Commander Andreas!
Komutan Andreas!
Command, sir.
Emredin efendim.
I sent Teokles after Osman, he still hasn't returned.
Teokles'i Osman'ın peşinden göndermiştim, hala dönmedi.
Find him, Andreas.
Onu bulun, Andreas.
Whatever happens.
Her ne olursa olsun.
Find it!
Onu bulun!
They hide what they know from us.
Asıl bildiklerini bizden saklarlar.
[Is there a destur?]
[Destur var mıdır?]
Come on, Samsa!
Gelesin Samsa!
We see your face from hunting to hunting.
Yüzünü sürek avından sürek avına görürüz.
What did you do well, Samsa.
Ne iyi ettin geldin Samsa.
We left you alone in that castle, we went.
Seni o melun kalede tek başına bıraktık gittik.
But...
Ama...
... you got out of the snake's well with your claws, ma'am.
...yılanın kuyusundan pençelerinle çıkmışsın maşallah.
We are the hereafter brothers with you, Samsa.
Biz seninle ahiret kardeşiyiz Samsa.
He was amazed at this time.
Kefere de şaşmıştır bu işe.
Here Basin.
Buyurasın.
What do you call this Teokles, to the voucher,
Kefere asıl bu Teokles dediğin...
... will ignite well when he doesn't return to the castle.
...kaleye dönmediğinde iyice tutuşacaktır.
Who is Teokles?
Teokles de kim ola?
It's the one they sent Ecel.
Ecel diye yolladıkları it.
Now we have it.
İmdi elimizde.
I know, I know Osman.
Bilirim Osman'ım bilirim.
I know my Aybars won't put their blood on the ground.
Aybars'ımın kanını yerde koymayacağını bilirim.
Teokles will take us to my Aybars brother's murderers.
Teokles bizi Aybars kardeşimin katillerine götürecek.
Thank you son.
Eyvallah oğul.
Thank you.
Eyvallah.
What was chopping the beech's stout?
Kayının yiğidine kıymak neymiş?
Then they will see.
O vakit görecekler.
For the sign of worship ...
İbreti alem için...
... if I do not peel their skin in pieces and stick to salt ...
...derilerini parça parça soyup tuza banmazsam...
... they should not tell me the son of Ertuğrul Gazi, Osman.
...bana da Ertuğrul Gazi oğlu Osman demesinler.
[Is there a destur, sir?]
[Destur var mıdır beyim?]
Come on, Boranalp.
Gelesin Boranalp.
No Boran?
Hayırdır Boran?
What is this face?
Ne bu suratının hali?
Osman Bey ...
Osman Bey'im...
Teokles fled, sir.
Teokles kaçmış beyim.
How did he escape?
Nasıl kaçmış?
Didn't I entrust him to you, Boran?
Ben onu sana emanet etmedim mi Boran?
Answer me!
Cevap ver!
How could you not protect a man with his hands tied?
Elleri ayakları bağlı olan bir adama nasıl sahip çıkamadın?
How not?
Nasıl yok?
Weren't you at the beginning?
Başında değil miydin?
I did your treatment as you said.
Beyim dediğin gibi tedavisini yaptım.
Then I went to the woods hunting so that he would not die of pain.
Sonra acından ölmesin diye ormana ava gittim.
When I returned, it was not there.
Döndüğümde yoktu.
They cut the rope with a dagger, sir.
İpini hançerle kesmişler beyim.
Someone has missed him.
Biri gelmiş kaçırmış onu.
Who did this?
Kim yaptı bunu?
Who?
Kim?
[Is there any destur, Mr. Dundar?]
[Destur var mıdır Dündar Bey'im?]
Come on, son.
Gelesin oğul.
You're coming.
Gelesin.
I have something to tell you, my father.
Sana anlatacaklarım vardır babam.
Tell me, let's see.
Hele anlat bakalım.
Osman.
Osman.
What did Osman do again?
Ne etti gene Osman?
He captured Teokles, one of the hunters of Sofia, right.
Sofya'nın avcılarından Teokles'i sağ ele geçirmiş.
Where is it?
Nerededir?
Don't worry, my father.
Meraklanmayasın babam.
I took him out of Osman's lair.
Osman'ın ininden çıkardım onu.
A knowledge ...
Bir malumat...
Did you get it?
...alabildiniz mi?
When Osman escaped from the castle, he followed him to catch up.
Osman kaleden kaçınca yakalamak için onu peşine takmış.
Who?
Kim?
Sofia.
Sofya.
Osman mistook Teokles.
Osman fena benzetmiş Teokles'i.
But now it is good.
Lakin imdi iyidir.
To that point ...
O kefere...
Where is it now?
...nerededir imdi?
We have the informal father.
Gayrı bizdedir babam.
This knowledge will save Bitinya from a great war.
Bu malumat Bitinya'yı büyük bir cenkten kurtaracaktır.
Joyful...
Sen...
... News to Gündüz Bey.
...Gündüz Bey'e haber salasın.
Lets.
Haydi.
Coyote to the nook ...
Çakal kuytuya...
... to the bear's lair.
...ayı inine.
His destination is clear.
Gideceği yer bellidir.
Castle.
Kale.
I will hit the jackal nook.
Çakalı kuytuda vuracağım.
I will drown the bear in his lair.
Ayıyı ininde boğacağım.
I Usman.
Osman'ım.
The scraps of this shroud do not cease.
Bu kefere artıklarının kahpeliği bitmez.
They may have played to attract you to the castle.
Seni kaleye çekmek için oyun etmiş olabilirler.
We should act as the tomb of Teokles, Bamsı Bey.
Teokles'e kaleyi mezar eylemeliyiz Bamsı Bey.
We must act ...
Eylemeliyiz ki...
No one should ever try to take a man from Osman Bey.
Bir daha hiç kimse Osman Bey'in elinden adam almaya kalkmasın.
Let the punishment we punish be legendary.
Keseceğimiz ceza da dillere destan olsun.
Samsa Sergeant.
Samsa Çavuş.
Hunting time in the castle.
Kalede av vaktidir.
Creature in the forest has recognized me well.
Ormanda mahlukat beni iyice tanıdı.
For some time they had been in a dead end.
Nicedir karşıma çıkmaz oldulardı.
I hope the castle will be fertile.
Kale bereketli olacak inşallah.
I would have stooped. You did it
Var olasın yiğidim. Şen eyledin.
I'm shaad.
Şad oldum.
Torero monopathy tu deu.
Torero monopati tu deu.
On the holy road of God ...
Tanrının kutsal yolunda...
... the bond in your eyes is gone now, Kalanoz.
...artık gözlerindeki bağ kalktı Kalanoz.
On the way to the Holy Margarite Church ...
Kutsal Margarit Kilisesi'nin yolunda...
... to fight the Turks until his death ...
...ölene kadar Türklerle savaşmaya...
... do you swear?
...yemin ediyor musun?
I would.
Ediyorum.
Whatever Turks know holy ...
Türklerin kutsal bildiği ne varsa...
... that he was going to cover his chest in front of him ...
...onun önünde göğsünü siper edeceğine...
... do you swear?
...yemin ediyor musun?
I would.
Ediyorum.
God bless you.
Tanrı seni kutsasın.
With all my soldiers printing the new market ...
Bütün askerlerimle yeni pazarı basıp...
I was ready to destroy the priests, Master Yannis.
...ahileri yok etmeye hazırdım Efendi Yannis.
I hope the Catalans can handle this job.
Umarım Katalanlar bu işi halledebilir.
I have not even the slightest doubt of this, Kalanoz.
Bundan en küçük şüphem bile yok Kalanoz.
When the time comes you will do much more.
Vakti gelince çok daha fazlasını yapacaksın.
But as you say ...
Ama senin de dediğin gibi...
... the castle should not be suspected.
...kaleden şüphe duyulmamalı.
Obama to ...
Obalarını...
... willow, her pastures ...
...söğüdü, otlaklarını...
... the days when we will turn everywhere into a blood lake ...
...her yeri kan gölüne çevireceğimiz günler...
... close to Kalanoz.
...yakın Kalanoz.
But now without getting our hands dirty ...
Ama şimdi elimizi kirletmeden...
... to our feet ...
...ayaklarımıza kadar gelen...
... we will clean the ahis.
...ahileri temizleyeceğiz.
More importantly...
Daha da önemlisi...
... we'll get back the holy trust.
...kutsal emaneti geri alacağız.
That wooden sword ...
O tahta kılıç...
... by Edabali's hand to the owner ...
...Edabali'nin eliyle sahibinin eline geçerse...
... we wake up the sleeping giant.
...uyuyan devi uyandırırız.
Do you understand me?
Anladın mı beni?
I get it, sir.
Anladım efendim.
Welcome, son.
Aramıza hoş geldin evlat.
Torero monopathy tu deu.
Torero monopati tu deu.
[What you told me warmed my edabali.]
[Anlattıkların bağrımı ısıttı Edabali.]
It...
Bu...
... there must be such a state that ...
...öyle bir devlet olmalı ki...
... justice must be resurrected with it ...
...adalet onunla yeniden dirilmeli...
Islam must find peace ...
...alemi İslam huzur bulmalı...
... the oppressors should tremble with fear ...
...zalimler korkudan titremeli...
...morality...
...ahlak...
... he must stand up with him.
...onunla kıyama kalkmalı.
Sadakallâhu'l-azim.
Sadakallâhu'l-azîm.
My God ...
Allah'ım...
... seeing everything ...
...her şeyi gören...
...omniscient...
...her şeyi bilen...
... you are the one who created everything.
...her şeyi yaratan sensin.
There is no secret to you.
Sana saklı yoktur.
Even the most unknown is obvious to you.
En bilinmeyen bile sana aşikardır.
These crazy passions inside me ...
İçimdeki bu deli tutkuları...
... dreams that are narrow in this rough ...
...bu kaba dar gelen hayalleri...
... my horizons beyond these lands ...
...bu toprakları aşan ufuklarımı...
... you know my dreams that won't fit in these lands.
...bu diyarlara sığmayacak hayallerimi bilen sensin.
This love ...
Bu aşkı...
... this passion ...
...bu tutkuyu...
... you who gave these dreams to my heart ...
...bu hayalleri gönlüme veren sen...
... your crew ...
...dermanını da...
... You give.
...verirsin.
Ya Rab ...
Ya rab...
... I had a dream ...
...ben bir düş gördüm...
... make this dream come true.
...bu düşü gerçek eyle.
Allow me to move my father's banner forward.
Babamın sancağını ileriye taşımamı bana nasip eyle.
I was in the soil when I opened my eyes.
Gözümü açtığımda topraktaydım.
How can you see beyond the waters.
Suların ötesini görmeyi sen nasip eyle.
All of us haze ...
Her yanımız pus...
...smoke...
...duman...
... surrounded by enemies.
...etrafımız düşmanlarla sarılı.
With the fire of İlay wordetullah ...
İlayı kelimetullah ateşi ile...
... to illuminate this darkness ...
...bu karanlığı aydınlatmayı...
... whatever you eat
...sen nasip eyle ye rabbi.
Amine.
Amin.
Emmi.
Emmi.
Good lesson and good lesson ...
İyi dersin hoş dersin de...
... I look at the road pus ...
...ben yola bakarım pus...
... I look at the water is cloudy.
...suya bakarım bulanık.
How will we trust these voyages after all these galleries?
Bunca gaileden sonra biz bu keferelere nasıl güveneceğiz?
They should not try to be cunning again.
Yine bir kurnazlık etmeye kalkmasınlar.
There is no cunning of fox, but ...
Tilkiden kurnazı yoktur ama...
... in the market ...
...pazar da...
Gündüz Bey is full of his post.
...onun postuyla doludur Gündüz Bey.
Emmi.
Emmi.
I think of Osman.
Ben Osman'ı düşünürüm.
When we heard that we delivered Teokles to the castle ...
Teokles'i kaleye teslim ettiğimizi duyunca...
... will be very angry.
...çok öfkelenecek çok.
We cannot predict what to do and what to do.
Ne yapacağını, ne edeceğini kestiremeyiz.
Mr. Gündüz.
Gündüz Bey.
What shall we do?
Ne edelim?
Should we fight with Kulucahisar so that Osman will be angry?
Osman öfkelenecek diye Kulucahisar ile cenk mi edelim?
Emmi.
Emmi.
My father Ertuğrul Bey will be back soon.
Babam Ertuğrul Bey yakında dönecek.
The killing of Tekfur ...
Tekfur'un öldürülmesinin de...
... who wants to know who is behind Aybars martyrdom.
...Aybars'ın şehit edilmesinin de ardında kimler var bilmek ister.
While Osman was seen in the castle that night ...
Osman da o gece kalede görülmüşken...
... let me not give the only proof we have.
...elimizdeki tek kanıtı onlara teslim etmeyelim derim ben.
Let's not surrender ...
Teslim etmeyelim de...
... what shall we have, my nephew?
...ne edelim yeğenim?
Do you think there are only traitors inside them?
Sen sadece onların içinde mi hainler var sanarsın?
What if they know that Teokles is in our hands?
Ya Teokles'in elimizde olduğunu biliyorlarsa?
Osman being seen in that castle ...
Osman'ın o kalede görülmesi...
... is not a reason for war for them?
...onlar için savaş sebebi sayılmaz mı?
Until my brother returns ...
Ağabeyim dönene kadar...
Our trade agreement with Kulucahisar will continue.
Kulucahisar ile yaptığımız ticaret anlaşması devam edecektir.
He has been struggling for years ...
Yıllarca uğraşıp...
... the peace that he established ...
...tesis ettiği sulhu...
... I can't break it because of Osman.
...Osman yüzünden bozamam ben.
Not that...
Lakin...
... nevertheless Osman does not know about it.
...yine de bundan Osman'ın haberi olmasın.
Now...
İmdi...
Where is it?
...nerededir o it?
I tied it to a nook behind the dark stream.
Karanlık derenin ardında bir kuytuya bağladım.
Even the devil cannot find his place.
Şeytan bile yerini bulamaz.
Let's go then.
Haydi gidelim o vakit.
Son.
Oğul.
Moon son.
Ay oğul.
Arbars son.
Arbars oğul.
Valiant son.
Yiğit oğul.
Hmm the ...
Hısını...
... if I see hungry ...
...aç görsem...
... I feed.
...doyurdum.
If I see naked ...
Çıplak görsem...
... I've rigged.
...donattım.
Like the hill ...
Tepe gibi...
... I stacked meat.
...et yığdım.
Blood is poured and ...
Kan akıtıp...
... I cut the victim.
...kurban kestim.
With wish ...
Dilek ile...
... with prayer ...
...dua ile...
... a son found it hard.
...bir oğul zor buldum.
I found you.
Seni buldum.
I found you, son.
Seni buldum oğul.
Esselamu alaikum and mercy.
Esselamu aleyküm ve rahmetullah.
It doesn't come off that fast.
Kefereden bu kadar hızlısı çıkmaz.
I know you Tursun.
Bildim seni Tursun.
Who are you?
Sen de kimsin?
Osman Bey sent.
Osman Bey gönderdi.
hayrolsun.
Hayrolsun.
Why did you come to the castle?
Kaleye kadar neden geldin?
I'll call someone named Teokles.
Teokles diye birini ararım.
Let me tell you from the beginning.
En başından anlat bakalım.
Osman Bey spoke fairly.
Osman Bey hakça konuşmuş.
Finally, the place to come is the castle.
Sonunda geleceği yer kaledir.
Not that...
Lakin...
... came from the night? I don't know him.
...geceden gelmiş midir? Onu bilmem.
Stop.
Hele dur.
Don't be bored right away.
Sıkma hemen canını.
We enter every hole of the castle, we find it, evelallah.
Kalenin her deliğine girer, onu buluruz evelallah.
What are these sounds?
Bu sesler de ne oluyor?
Mr. Dundar.
Dündar Bey.
Mr. Gündüz.
Gündüz Bey.
Teokles next to them.
Yanlarındaki de Teokles.
It is now clear who has bought it.
Onu kimin aldığı imdi belli oldu.
Dervish father!
Derviş baba!
Dervish father.
Derviş baba.
You gave love.
Aşk verdin.
We became Bahtiyar.
Bahtiyar olduk.
Astaghfurullah, astaghfurullah.
Estağfurullah, estağfurullah.
We actually saw you ...
Asıl biz sizleri gördük...
... we got love, comrade Nizamettin.
...aşk aldık Nizamettin yoldaşım.
As soon as possible ...
En kısa vakitte...
... we wish to establish a love ring with the lovers.
...yarenlerle muhabbet halkası kurmak dileriz.
We opened the heart cafe.
Gönül kafesini açtık.
The sentence went to news.
Cümle canlara haber gitti.
You can be informed too.
Sen de haberdar olasın.
Our head is on our eyes, Derviş baba.
Başımız gözümüz üstüne Derviş baba.
Where are they?
Neredeler?
Those who stand at the potter bench.
Şu çömlekçi tezgahının başında duranlar.
I was assassinated in your castle.
Kalenizde suikaste uğradım.
I thought it was not experienced.
Yaşanmamış saydım.
You accused my nephew of murder ...
Yeğenimi cinayetle suçladınız...
... I hit the cinema.
...sineme çektim.
Burçin, the bride of Bamsı Bey, one of the lords of our obese ...
Obamızın beylerinden Bamsı Bey'in gelini Burçin'i...
... you battered.
...darp ettiniz.
I shut up.
Sustum.
My daughter ...
Kızımı...
... you missed Aygül.
...Aygül'ümü kaçırdınız.
I closed my eyes.
Gözlerimi yumdum.
After my nephew Osman ...
Yeğenim Osman'ın peşine...
... you released this killer.
...bu katili saldınız.
I brought it back to you with my hands.
Ellerimle size geri getirdim.
Mr. Dundar.
Dündar Bey.
We are very unhappy with these.
Biz de bunların olmasından dolayı çok mutsuzuz.
But remember that ...
Ancak unutmayın ki...
... my husband was killed.
...kocam öldürüldü.
Your home...
Senin evin...
... was my friend too.
...benim de dostumdu.
The only suspect of your friend's death ...
Dostunuzun ölümünün tek zanlısı...
... your nephew is Osman.
...yeğenin Osman'dır.
He could not even stand trial and escaped from our pen.
O ise yargılanmayı bile göze alamayıp kalemizden kaçtı.
You too, to execute it ...
Sen de onu infaz etmek için...
... you went after a pack of murderers.
...peşine bir katil sürüsü saldın.
Mr. Dundar.
Dündar Bey.
If Osman is tried ...
Eğer Osman yargılanır...
... and if he proves to be innocent, there will be no problem.
...ve suçsuz olduğunu ispat ederse hiçbir problem kalmayacak.
If only...
Keşke...
... to show your good intentions ...
...iyi niyetinizi göstermek için...
... by relying on our justice ...
...bizim adaletimize itimat edip...
... if you brought Osman rather than that.
...bunu değil de Osman'ı getirseydiniz.
I saw Osman last in this castle, Kalanoz.
Osman'ı en son bu kalede gördüm Kalanoz.
If he escapes from a fortress where you get his security ...
Güvenliğini senin aldığın bir kaleden kaçıyorsa...
... I have nothing to do.
...benim yapacak bir şeyim yoktur.
Osman...
Osman...
... it will be prosecuted.
...yargılanacak.
But he's not here.
Lakin burada değil.
Greeks too ...
Rumların da...
... there are also apricots ...
...kayıların da olduğu...
... in a Willow court.
...bir Söğüt mahkemesinde.
I'm just chasing the truth, Mr. Dundar.
Ben sadece gerçeğin peşindeyim Dündar Bey.
Your offer has been accepted.
Teklifiniz kabul edilmiştir.
So here you go ...
O halde buyurun...
... Dundar Bey.
...Dündar Bey.
Get out of your room, Teokles.
Odana çık Teokles.
Get some rest.
Biraz dinlen.
Door!
Kapı!
Storm...
Boran...
... you eat the horses.
...sen atları yemleyesin.
Thank you sir.
Eyvallah beyim.
Konuralp and you stay here.
Konuralp sen de burada kalasın.
Thief!
Hırsız!
Help!
Yardım edin!
He took my pouch!
Kesemi aldı!
The gold is gone!
Gitti altınlar!
Running!
Koşun!
Bey.
Beyim.
Sir, forgive me, sir.
Beyim ne olur canımı bağışla beyim.
What will you be, sir?
Ne olursun beyim.
Bey.
Beyim.
Nizamettin Bey!
Nizamettin Bey!
I sentenced these two thieves.
Bu iki hırsızın da cezasını kestim.
If I see them here again ...
Bir daha onları burada görürsem...
... well know that they will die.
...öleceklerini iyice bellet.
They deserved that you fined.
Hak etmişler ki cezalarını kesmişsin.
May you exist, Osman Bey.
Var olasın Osman Bey.
First of all, Nizamettin Bey should do your duty properly.
Evvela sen de vazifeni düzgün yapasın Nizamettin Bey.
Remember your vow here that there will be no particle musk injustice.
Burada zerre miskal adaletsizlik olmayacak diye ettiğin yemini hatırla.
If there is such an event again ...
Bir daha böyle bir hadise olursa...
... I ask your account from you.
...hesabını senden sorarım.
The language is long, the long hand, the long hand.
Dili uzun olan dilinden, eli uzun olan elinden olur.
Osman Bey found what he deserved.
Hak ettiğini buldu Osman Bey.
Take those thieves.
Götürün şu hırsızları.
Are you looking for my mother?
Anacığım keseni mi ararsın?
Thank you very much, god bless you.
Çok sağ ol, tanrı seni korusun.
Aren't you Osman Bey?
Sen Osman Bey değil misin?
Ertuğrul Bey's son.
Ertuğrul Bey'in evladı.
You're brave like your father.
Baban gibi yiğitsin.
God loves you ...
Tanrı seni sevdiklerine...
May he forgive us in the just hands of gentlemen like you.
...bizi de sizin gibi beylerin adaletli ellerine bağışlasın.
Thank you very much.
Çok sağ olasın.
God bless you.
Tanrı sizi korusun.
Thank you, my dear.
Sağ olasın anacığım.
Aslı and Kerem.
Aslı ile Kerem.
I tried so hard, it is finally over.
Çok uğraş verdim, sonunda bitti.
Very nice thank you.
Eline sağlık çok güzel olmuş.
But the only thing that ends is not tiles ...
Lakin biten tek şey çini değil...
... the treatment of his horse is over.
...atının tedavisi de bitti.
Yaman bahadır, son.
Yaman bahadırsın evlat.
May your sword of justice be permanent.
Adalet dağıtan kılıcın daim olsun.
Thank you dervish father.
Eyvallah derviş baba.
Where do you come from? Where do you go?
Nereden gelirsin? Nereye gidersin?
We came from Hay, we go to hu, son.
Hay'dan geldik, hu'ya gideriz evlat.
Navigation with our heart ...
Kalbimizle seyrü- süluk...
... we travel with our feet.
...ayağımızla seyahat ederiz.
Blessed, dervish father.
Seyahatin mübarek olsun derviş baba.
God bless you.
Allah razı olsun.
I've been traveling all this breath.
Onca nefestir seyahat ederim.
I didn't come across like this.
Böylesine denk gelmedim.
The pouch does not give a pouch value, but ...
Kese kese akçeler değerini vermez ama...
... how expensive is that, girl?
...pahası nedir bunun kızım?
Do not mention it.
Estağfurullah.
Akçe comes from the servant, but Allah gives abundance.
Akçe kuldan gelir ama bereketi Allah verir.
My dervish father is my gift to you.
Sana hediyemdir derviş baba.
May there be my daughter.
Var olasın kızım.
May you be old in two worlds.
İki cihanda bahtiyar olasın.
When yar is with yar ...
Yar, yar ile olunca...
... becomes old.
...bahtiyar olur.
It would be Bahtiyar.
Bahtiyar olur.
May God be with you.
Allah'a emanet olun.
Soundly.
Selametle.
No, Osman Bey.
Hayırdır Osman Bey.
Nice wolf wears lambskin.
Nice kurt, kuzu postunu giyer.
Nice traitor ...
Nice hain de...
... looks like a crown and a cardigan and a dervish.
...tac ile hırka ile derviş gibi görülür.
I never watched this man know this.
Hiç gözüm tutmadı bu adamı bilesin.
What treacherous gives up traitor.
Ne hain hainliğinden vazgeçer.
From what cruel cruelty.
Ne zalim zalimliğinden.
As long as we are in the future.
Yeter ki biz sırat-ı müstakim üzre olalım.
Gonca Hatun, the bench is entrusted to you.
Gonca Hatun, tezgah sana emanettir.
You don't worry.
Merak etmeyesin.
This is Osman Bey, son of Ertuğrul Gazi.
Ertuğrul Gazi'nin oğlu Osman Bey bu demek.
In the raid, we will open a business.
Baskında başımıza iş açacak.
Kill Osman in the raid.
Baskında Osman'ı öldürün.
But Edabali's daughter Bala ...
Ama Edabali'nin kızı Bala'yı...
...I want it alive.
...canlı istiyorum.
We will learn from him what we want.
İstediğimizi ondan öğreneceğiz.
How did you know that Bala Hatun was, sir?
Bala Hatun olduğunu nasıl anladınız efendim?
To become the disciple of Ahi Evran ...
Ahi Evran'ın müridi olmak için...
I saw it when I arrived at the door.
...kapısına vardığımda görmüştüm.
He was with his father.
Babasının yanındaydı.
It was small then.
Küçüktü o vakitler.
But his eyes ...
Ama gözleri...
... never changed.
...hiç değişmemiş.
Spruce.
Alacam.
It came here like the wind.
Buraya kadar rüzgar gibi geldi.
How did you do well, Alaca, Osman Bey?
Nasıl iyi ettin Alaca'mı Osman Bey?
What was his healing?
Şifası neymiş bunun?
Healing several versions ointment.
Şifası birkaç sürüm merhem.
And Bala Hatun, who had a love for you.
Bir de sana olan sevgisi imiş Bala Hatun.
To enter the dangers with you ...
Seninle tehlikeleri girebilmek için...
... kept looking impatient.
...sabırsızlanıp durdu.
You see, Osman Bey.
Gördün işte Osman Bey.
I am a strange craftsman in the hereafter.
Ben ahiret yolunda garip bir zanaatkarım.
Yesterday when I saw you tear at the beginning of the horse ...
Dün atın başında seni gözü yaşlı gördüğüm an...
I made a promise to myself.
...kendime bir söz verdim.
What was this saying?
Ne sözüymüş bu?
Whoever spills one drop of tears from the eyes of this chick ...
Her kim bu hatunun gözünden tek bir damla yaş dökerse...
I said ... my dear enemy.
...benim can düşmanımdır dedim.
Not our enemies ...
Bizi düşmanlarımız değil...
... but our loved ones hurt Osman Bey.
...ancak sevdiklerimiz incitir Osman Bey.
May you be good cheer.
Sen müsterih olasın.
Mr. Osman!
Osman Bey!
What do you want, bully?
Ne istersin zorba?
Mr. Alişar has heard news everywhere, sir, he will call you.
Alişar Bey her yere haber saldı beyim, seni aratır.
Not as a banner, as a hunting companion ...
Sancak beyi olarak değil av yoldaşın olarak...
He said he wanted to host you in his mansion.
...seni konağında misafir etmek istediğini söyledi.
Thank you.
Eyvallah.
Let's get together.
Birlikte varalım.
Excuse me, Bala Hatun.
Müsaadenle Bala Hatun.
I will come to see you at thesis time.
Tez vakitte seni görmeye geleceğim.
Osman Bey has a nod to you.
Osman Bey'in selamı var sana.
Stop!
Dur!
Crap in Byzantium ...
Bizans'ta kahpelik...
... valiant does not end in registration.
...kayıda yiğit bitmez.
Mr. Osman!
Osman Bey!
You are welcome.
Hoş gelmişsin.
We welcome Alişar Bey.
Hoş gördük Alişar Bey.
Here Basin.
Buyurasın.
Let me offer you sherbet sherbet Osman.
Sana reyhan şerbeti ikram edeyim Osman Bey.
You threw the Kulucahisar Castle like a cotton ball.
Kulucahisar Kalesi'ni hallaç pamuğu gibi atmışsın.
Our breath is on them.
Nefesimiz üzerlerinde.
They will see us even in their shadows.
Gölgelerinde bile bizi görecekler.
To their slanders ...
İftiralarına da...
... we do not give passages to your cocks, evelallah.
...kahpeliklerine de geçit vermeyiz evelallah.
I know you didn't kill Tekfur.
Tekfur'u senin öldürmediğini bilirim.
If you killed ...
Eğer sen öldürseydin...
... no one would hear the soul.
...kimsenin ruhu duymazdı.
You took out your hand from the sinister castle.
O uğursuz kaleden elini kolunu sallayarak çıkardın.
From you...
Senden...
... if I had any suspicion ...
...zerre kadar şüphem olsaydı...
... as a starboard ...
...sancak beyi olarak...
... finds you before you suck, throws you into the dungeon ...
...seni emminden evvel bulur, zindana atar...
I would take him to court before the woman.
...kadının huzurunda mahkemeye çıkartırdım.
I will drown them in their slander, Alişar Bey.
Onları iftiralarında boğacağım Alişar Bey.
Finding the murderers of Tekfur and my brother ...
Tekfur'un da kardeşimin de katillerini bulup...
... I will see their accounts.
...hesaplarını göreceğim.
I would like a court for this.
Bunun için ben de mahkeme isterim.
Coming to the court with my own foot ...
Kendi ayağımla mahkemenin huzuruna gelip...
I would like to be tried.
...yargılanmak isterim.
From this table ...
Bu sofradan...
... the last time we got up ...
...en son kalktığımızda...
... we were full of hope.
...içimiz umut dolu idi.
Be sure, Princess Sofia.
Emin olun Prenses Sofya.
The death of my friend Yorgo Polos ...
Dostum Yorgo Polos'un ölümü...
... after you ...
...sizden sonra...
... hurt us the most.
...en çok bizi yaraladı.
After serving my husband's murderer sentence ...
Kocamın katili cezasını çektikten sonra...
... we will repeat that friendship again.
...o dostluğu tekrar yineleyeceğiz.
Mr. Dundar.
Dündar Bey.
A permanent peace in this land ...
Bu topraklarda kalıcı bir sulh...
... was our biggest dream with Yorgo Polos.
...Yorgo Polos ile en büyük hayalimizdi.
And even the most important legacy he left ...
Ve dahi bıraktığı en mühim miras da...
...This is.
...budur.
Sir.
Efendim.
Teokles was killed.
Teokles öldürülmüş.
How?
Nasıl?
Osman!
Osman!
He did it.
O yaptı bunu.
Osman is not even here, princess. How come?
Osman burada bile değil prenses. Nasıl olur?
Nobody else than Osman could have done this.
Bunu Osman'dan başkası yapmış olamaz.
That's enough!
Bu kadar yeter!
Tekfur ...
Tekfur'u da...
killed the traitors inside your castle.
...kalenizin içindeki hainler öldürdü.
Almost...
Neredeyse...
... we would believe you.
...size inanacaktık.
We will discuss this in court, Mr. Dundar.
Bunu mahkemede konuşacağız Dündar Bey.
In court ...
Mahkemede...
... if my nephew is justified and your hostility still continues ...
...yeğenim aklanır da husumetiniz hala devam ederse...
... let alone break where he thinks.
...gayrı inceldiği yerden kopsun.
Cenk is cenk ...
Cenk ise cenk...
... peace is ...
...sulh ise...
peace.
sulh.
And this...
Bunu da...
... you know that.
...böyle bilesiniz.
Obviously with Bamsı Bey's son ...
Belli ki Bamsı Bey'in evladıyla...
... you think that Tekfur's murderers are the same people.
...Tekfur'un katillerinin aynı kişiler olduğunu düşünürsün.
With this reason, he sneaks into the castle and ...
Bu cihetle kaleye gizlice girip...
... you wanted to talk to Tekfur.
...Tekfur ile konuşmak istedin.
Is that so?
Öyle mi?
It is true.
Doğrudur.
I talked to Tekfur before I died.
Ölmeden evvel Tekfur ile konuştum da.
Did you speak?
Konuştun mu?
So tell me all you know.
O halde bütün bildiklerini anlat bana.
Before Tekfur died, Alişar Bey told me that the fitna spread from his own castle.
Tekfur ölmeden evvel fitnenin kendi kalesinden yayıldığını bana söyledi Alişar Bey.
I was the only one he trusted.
Tek güvendiği bendim.
Neither wife nor commander Kalanoz.
Ne karısı ne komutanı Kalanoz.
Cenk is at the door, Osman Bey.
Cenk kapıdadır Osman Bey.
It is not time to be silent either.
Susulacak da vakit değildir.
With Kayi ...
Kayılarla...
... Kulucahisar's cengi ...
...Kulucahisar'ın cengi...
... you took a look ...
...bir bakmışsın...
... Seljuk became Byzantine war.
...Selçuklu, Bizans cengi olmuş.
Commander Kalanoz with Princess Sofia ...
Prenses Sofya ile Komutan Kalanoz...
he asked you to go to court.
...senin mahkemeye çıkmanı istemiş.
You have also escaped from the dungeon.
Sen zindandan da kaçmışsın.
The court should be established on our land.
Mahkeme bizim topraklarımıza kurulmalı.
Why is that?
Neden?
Why would you hesitate?
Neden çekinirsin?
Princess Sofia ...
Prenses Sofya...
... Commander Kalanoz ...
...Komutan Kalanoz...
... they wanted to kill me before going to court.
...mahkemeye çıkmadan beni öldürmek istediler.
For this, he must have strong evidence in his hand.
Bunun için elinde kuvvetli bir delil olmalı.
You can be sure, Alişar Bey.
Olduğundan emin olasın Alişar Bey.
Everyone will see when the court is established.
Mahkeme kurulduğunda herkes görecek.
I will prove that they are both murderers in court.
Mahkemede ikisinin de katil olduğunu ispat edeceğim.
What about you, Osman Bey?
Sen ne dersin Osman Bey?
Where does this end? Have you ever thought?
Bu işin sonu nereye varır? Düşündün mü hiç?
If you stand by the truth ...
Sen hakikatin yanında durursan...
... not me they are afraid.
...ben değil onlar korksun.
If they were the target of a hunter like you ...
Senin gibi bir avcının hedefi oldularsa...
... I say they are ruined.
...halleri haraptır derim.
If we pull those two jackals into our own hunt ...
O iki çakalı kendi avlağımıza çekersek...
... I'll sing like a nightingale in court.
...mahkemede bülbül gibi öttüreceğim.
As long as...
Yeter ki...
... trust me, Alişar Bey.
...sen bana itimat et Alişar Bey.
Be sure, Osman Bey.
Emin ol Osman Bey.
I will do my part.
Ben üzerime düşeni yapacağım.
We smashed them!
Parçaladık onları!
The eyes of Catalonia are black children ...
Katalonya'nın gözü kara evlatları...
The lion-hearted warriors of Prince Salvador ...
...Prens Salvador'un aslan yürekli savaşçıları...
... to leave scary stories behind you ...
...ardınızda korkunç hikayeler bırakmaya...
...Are you ready?
...hazır mısınız?
We're ready!
Hazırız!
Are you ready?
Hazır mısınız?
To us...
Bize...
... they will say Prince Salvador's brutal soldiers.
...Prens Salvador'un acımasız askerleri diyecekler.
They will scare their children with us.
Çocuklarını bizimle korkutacaklar.
Pregnant women will make low when we hear our name.
Gebe kadınlar ismimizi duyunca düşük yapacak.
The hair of young men will grow out of fear.
Genç erkeklerin korkudan saçları ağaracak.
For Prince Salvador!
Prens Salvador için!
For the sea of ​​loot waiting for us!
Bizi bekleyen ganimet denizi için!
Now is the time of war!
Şimdi savaş vaktidir!
Salvador! Salvador!
Salvador! Salvador!
Salvador!
Salvador!
Are you sure, Samsa sergeant?
Emin misin Samsa çavuş?
Osman Bey, as I believe.
İmanım gibi Osman Bey.
Emmi.
Emmi.
My brother.
Ağabeyim.
Batur.
Batur.
I saw it with my eyes.
Gözlerim ile gördüm.
That shroud called Teokles ...
O Teokles denen kefere...
... was between Dündar Bey and Gündüz Bey. Batur behind them.
...Dündar Bey ile Gündüz Bey'in arasındaydı. Arkalarında da Batur.
So the guy Sofia was chasing after me to kill me ...
Demek Sofya'nın beni öldürmek için peşime taktığı adamı...
... will take me to the murderers of my brother Aybars ...
...beni kardeşim Aybars'ın katillerine götürecek...
... they delivered the most important trump card to the castle?
...en mühim kozu kaleye teslim ettiler he?
My brother Emmim and my brother were also there.
Emmim de ağabeyim de obadaydı.
So...
Demek ki...
... going to the cave after Boran ...
...Boran'ın peşinden mağaraya giden...
... Batur, who kidnapped Teokles.
...Teokles'i kaçıran Batur.
Batur huh?
Batur he?
Batur he!
Batur he!
Batur.
Batur.
Batur!
Batur!
This will pay off the betrayal.
Bu ihanetin hesabını ödeyecek.
What will you do, Osman Bey?
Ne edeceksin Osman Bey?
I will bring them to the fairest court, Konuralp.
Onları en adil mahkemeye çıkaracağım Konuralp.
I will set up the court!
Mahkemeyi ben kuracağım!
My witnesses are my martyred brother Aybars.
Tanıklarım şehit kardeşim Aybars.
It will be Yorgo Polos, who was slaughtered in dishonest.
Kahpece katledilen Yorgo Polos olacak.
The woman of the court I will establish is my anger.
Kuracağım mahkemenin kadısı öfkem.
I'll have a hangover!
Celladı pusatım olacak!
I will judge them.
Onları ben yargılayacağım.
Because there is a good in every evil ...
Her şerde bir hayır vardır diye...
... they did not say wasted Gündüz.
...boşa dememişler Gündüz.
You're right, Emmi.
Doğru dersin Emmi.
The death of Teokles is also my brother Osman ...
Teokles'in ölümü kardeşim Osman'ın da...
Thank God he proved ... innocent.
...masum olduğunu ispatladı çok şükür.
You came on time, girl.
Vakitlice geldin kızım.
My pain was burned.
Bağrım yandı idi.
Healing, my father.
Şifa olsun bey babam.
Thanks.
Sağ olasın.
Bismillahirrahmanirrahim.
Bismillahirrahmanirrahim.
The game he's playing has also appeared ...
Ettikleri oyun da ortaya çıktı ya...
... they cannot slander Osman informally.
...bundan gayrı Osman'a iftira da atamazlar.
Emmi.
Emmi.
We wish to see business and trade with these guys.
Biz bu adamlarla iş görmek, ticaret yapmak dileriz de...
... zanlım by ...
...zanlımca...
... this castle boils like a cauldron.
...bu kale kazan gibi kaynar.
Tekfur was first assassinated.
Önce Tekfur suikasti.
Now ...
İmdi de...
... the man called Teokles.
...Teokles denilen adam.
Obviously there is a big conflict behind the stone walls.
Belli ki taş duvarlar ardında büyük bir çatışma var.
Good or nephew.
İyi ya yeğenim.
The more it boils there ...
Orası ne kadar kaynarsa...
... it will benefit us so much.
...bize de o kadar yarar.
You say good.
İyi dersiniz.
Have a nice lesson ...
Hoş dersiniz de...
... if Osman is not as innocent as we think?
...ya Osman zannettiğimiz kadar masum değil ise?
What will happen to Dundar Bey and Batur, sir?
Dündar Bey ile Batur ne olacak beyim?
All will pay their account!
Hepsi hesabını ödeyecek!
Samsa sergeant, you're out of here.
Samsa çavuş, buradan gayrı sen durasın.
Do not worry, we are with Osman Bey.
Merak etmeyesin, biz Osman Bey'in yanındayız.
Bala Hatun laughs in your eyes.
Gözlerinin içi güler Bala Hatun.
I'll come.
Alacam geldi.
How was it?
Nasıl olmuş Alaca?
According to the smile of the face ...
Yüzün güldüğüne göre...
... Osman Bey has obviously made a good horse.
...Osman Bey iyi etmiş atını belli ki.
I don't know if he has healing.
Elinde şifa mı vardır bilmem.
He beat my horse well overnight.
Bir gecede iyi etmiş atımı.
I don't know if you have any healing.
Elinde şifa var mıdır bilmem.
However, since he did well overnight ...
Lakin bir gecede iyi edip getirdiğine göre...
... his heart is not empty.
...gönlü boş değildir.
What do you mean, Gonca Hatun?
Ne demeye getirirsin Gonca Hatun?
Take out the pods in your mouth.
Çıkar ağzındaki baklayı.
I asked the customers from the apricot.
Kayılardan gelen müşterilere sual ettim.
Osman Bey does not have a chick.
Osman Bey'in hatunu yoktur.
Stout like that ...
Onun gibi yiğidin...
... necessarily has a baby.
...illa ki bir yavuklusu vardır.
I asked thoroughly, investigated.
İyice sordum, soruşturdum.
There is no cub.
Yavuklusu da yoktur.
Both ...
Hem...
... why would you tell me these Gonca Hatun?
...bana neden anlatırsın bunları Gonca Hatun?
I saw how he looked at you on the counter.
Tezgahta sana nasıl baktığını gördüm.
[Aslı and Kerem.]
[Aslı ile Kerem.]
Very nice thank you.
Eline sağlık, çok güzel olmuş.
Not that...
Lakin...
... the only thing that ends is not tiles ...
...biten tek şey çini değil...
... the treatment of his horse is over.
...atının tedavisi de bitti.
Aygül Hatun put herself in danger without blinking.
Aygül Hatun için gözünü kırpmadan kendini tehlikeye attı.
E is the daughter of the suck.
E emmisinin kızı.
What would he do?
Ne edecekti?
Would he let him die?
Ölmesine göz mü yumacaktı?
In a well-known heap like Osman ...
Hem Osman gibi namlı bir yiğide...
... does it ever work?
...yaraşır mı hiç?
Or are you jealous?
Yoksa kıskandın mı?
Put those pots on the stalls.
Şu çömlekleri tezgahlara koy.
A vacant bench is also a poll.
Boşalan tezgahları da bir yoklayıver.
Leave the stub, Bala Hatun.
İnadı bırak Bala Hatun.
I do not have the benches or polls ...
Ben tezgahları yoklarım yoklamasına da...
... you wipe a heart.
...sen bir gönlünü yoklayıver.
Thanks.
Sağ olasın.
They could be the market.
Pazar ola bacılar.
Become a market.
Pazar ola.
You are welcome.
Hoş gelmişsin.
Nice to you, chick.
Hoş gördük hatun.
There's a white horse in the stable, they said it's yours.
Ahırda ak bir at var, senin olduğunu dediler.
What happened to Alaca?
Ne olmuş Alaca'ma?
He became grumpy and stopped.
Durduk yere huysuzlaştı.
Now he is sick. Come and take a look.
İmdi de can çekişir. Gelip bir bakasın bacım.
Let me see Gonca.
Ben bir bakayım Gonca.
Okay Bala Hatun.
Tamam Bala Hatun.
May you compare the counter.
Tezgaha mukayet olasın.
You don't worry, baby.
Merak etmeyesin bacım.
I ate it!
Yettim bacım!
You were so beautiful.
Pek de güzelmişsin.
It will be a pity for this beauty.
Yazık olacak bu güzelliğe.
Take it!
Götürün!
Attack the market! Put everyone through the sword!
Pazara saldırın! Herkesi kılıçtan geçirin!
Move!
Yürüyün!
Welcome Osman Bey!
Hoş geldiniz Osman Bey!
This is what you do ...
Bu yaptığın...
... he won't be near you, osman.
...yanına kalmaz osman.
Excuse for romance ...
Kahpeliğin bahanesi...
... betrayal is not compensated.
...ihanetin telafisi olmaz.
What do you do, sir?
Beyim ne edersin?
You're still chasing the damn, son.
Hala kahpelik peşindesin emmi oğlu.
Now!
İmdi!
Listen to me!
Beni iyi dinleyin!
Who sows fitna ...
Kim ki fitne eker...
... treachery ...
...hainlik yaparsa...
Who is ...
Kim ki...
... if he tries to turn around after me!
...arkamdan oyun çevirmeye kalkarsa!
I!
Ben!
Ertuğrul Gazi's son Osman!
Ertuğrul Gazi oğlu Osman!
The great post where my father was founded.
Babamın kurulduğu ulu post.
A full-fledged banner that we live in.
Gölgesinde yaşadığımız tamgalı sancak.
And...
Ve...
... I carry in my waist ...
...belimde taşıdığım...
... on my black pus ...
...kara pusadım üzerine...
... and I drink!
...and içerim ki!
I'm not hurt!
Acımam!
Flood washes ...
Sel olur yıkar...
... it will be a fire!
...ateş olur yakarım!
Ear that doesn't hear my warnings ...
Uyarılarımı duymayan kulağı...
... the language to say words on ...
...üzerine laf söyleyecek dili...
... I'll cut it up!
...keser atarım!
It...
Bu...
... so to know ...
...böylece biline...
... so be said!
...böylece söylene!